<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Web Application Security Fundamentals on Infuse</title><link>https://infusedev.safetag.org/ar/learning-path/4/</link><description>Recent content in Web Application Security Fundamentals on Infuse</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>ar</language><atom:link href="https://infusedev.safetag.org/ar/learning-path/4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Infrastructure Vulnerabilities</title><link>https://infusedev.safetag.org/ar/learning-path/4/module-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infusedev.safetag.org/ar/learning-path/4/module-1/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="حالة-استخدام">حالة استخدام&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>بينما يركز مسار التعلّم هذا على أمان تطبيقات الويب، تعمل تطبيقات الويب بالإضافة إلى العديد من أجزاء البنية التحتية للبرمجيات. ستؤدي أي ثغرة أمنية في البنية التحتية الخاصة بالتطبيق إلى تعريض التطبيق للخطر، وبالتالي فإن فهم بعض أمن البنية التحتية جزءٌ من فهم أمن التطبيقات.
عند فحص تطبيق ويب إما لأغراض تقييم الثغرات الأمنية أو الرقابة الأمنية أو لفحص ثغرة، يجب على الممارس فهم المجموعة الأساسية من التكنولوجيات التي توفر البيئة اللازمة لتشغيل التطبيق أثناء البحث عن ثغرات في تلك المجموعة.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://infusedev.safetag.org/ar/learning-path/4/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infusedev.safetag.org/ar/learning-path/4/introduction/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are many ways in which adversaries could try to attack websites, including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Denial of expression: website takedown, website defacement, denial of service&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Accessing sensitive data: exploiting access controls or other vulnerabilities to access information for instance in application databases, private files or systems, private inboxes or members’ areas&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Implanting malware ( ‘watering hole’ attacks): using access to a website to place malicious or misleading code for the purpose of achieving objectives on visitor devices&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lateral movement (compromising other systems): gaining access to whole servers, cloud infrastructure, or office or home infrastructure&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Surveillance of visitors: obtaining information on IPs or identities of visitors to a website or users of a web application&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Supply chain compromise: compromising distribution services for software, building processes of software, or for component libraries of software in order to achieve malicious objectives on users of the targeted software&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Impersonation of websites: for purposes of phishing, muddying of reputation, and malware/spyware distribution&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Traffic injection (downgrading attacks): exploiting infrastructure or communications configuration weaknesses for the purpose of inserting malicious content into otherwise good traffic&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Web application security is a deep domain of technical knowledge with many areas of specialization. This learning path will provide you with a general understanding of web application vulnerabilities and how some of the more common ones work. It should help you understand the types of vulnerabilities that commonly exist in web applications, capabilities that these vulnerabilities give to attackers, and how, in general, to eliminate or mitigate these vulnerabilities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data Validation</title><link>https://infusedev.safetag.org/ar/learning-path/4/module-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infusedev.safetag.org/ar/learning-path/4/module-2/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="حالة-استخدام">حالة استخدام&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>تتعلق فئة شائعة من الثغرات في تطبيقات الويب بالطريقة التي يعالج بها التطبيق البيانات التي يقدمها مستخدمو الموقع، ويكثر استخدام فئة الثغرات الأمنية هذه من قبل المهاجمين للتحكم بالكامل بمواقع الويب المستهدفة، وغالبًا ما يمكن اكتشافها عبر التقنيات الآلية. يُعدّ فهم آليات ثغرات التحقق من صحة البيانات مفيدًا للغاية أيضًا لتوضيح مواضيع الأمان المعقدة.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="الأهداف">الأهداف&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>بعد استكمال هذا الموضوع الفرعي، يجب أن يكون الممارسون قادرين على القيام بما يلي:
فهم الأنواع الشائعة من ثغرات التحقق من صحة البيانات
فهم الآثار المحتملة لهذه الأنواع من الثغرات
فهم آليات عمل هذه الثغرات
فهم كيفية منع ثغرات هذه بشكل عام&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Authentication</title><link>https://infusedev.safetag.org/ar/learning-path/4/module-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infusedev.safetag.org/ar/learning-path/4/module-3/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In any website that has user logins, it’s important that the site protects user accounts from unauthorized access, and also that the account credentials themselves are protected. This subtopic outlines the most common areas of authentication where web application flaws appear.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, practitioners should be able to do the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Understand common types of authentication vulnerabilities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Understand the potential impacts of those types of vulnerabilities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Understand the mechanisms by which those vulnerabilities work&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Understand, in broad strokes, how those vulnerabilities can be prevented&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="main-section">Main Section&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Authentication is the process by which a user of a system proves that they are who they claim they are. It is the foundation upon which access control is built. Typically, a user will supply a piece of information that identifies them (username, email address, phone number, etc.) and a piece of secret information that validates that identity (commonly a password or passphrase, though alternative or additional methods such as a security keys, WebAuthn, and Passkeys are gaining popularity). This subtopic will cover a few vulnerability classes that are common and high-impact in web applications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>التخويل</title><link>https://infusedev.safetag.org/ar/learning-path/4/module-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infusedev.safetag.org/ar/learning-path/4/module-4/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="حالة-استخدام">حالة استخدام&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>في أي موقع ويب يحتوي على مستخدمين بمستويات مختلفة من القدرات (مثل المشاهدين مقابل المحررين) أو يحتوي على معلومات سرية للمستخدمين ومن المهم أن يحمي الموقع هذه الميزات و/أو هذه البيانات من الأشخاص الذين ليس لديهم إذن لاستخدام هذه الميزات و/أو التفاعل مع هذه البيانات.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="الأهداف">الأهداف&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>بعد استكمال هذا الموضوع الفرعي، يجب أن يكون الممارسون قادرين على القيام بما يلي:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>فهم الأنواع الشائعة من ثغرات التخويل&lt;/li>
&lt;li>فهم الآثار المحتملة لهذه الأنواع من الثغرات&lt;/li>
&lt;li>فهم آليات عمل هذه الثغرات&lt;/li>
&lt;li>فهم كيفية منع ثغرات هذه بشكل عام&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="العرض">العرض&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="المعرفة-الأساسية">المعرفة الأساسية&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>يُعدّ التخويل عملية تأكد من أن مستخدم النظام لديه إذن لتنفيذ إجراء أو إنشاء/قراءة/تحرير/حذف جزء من البيانات في هذا النظام ومنع هذه الإجراءات إذا لم يكن لدى المستخدم إذن، وبشكل عام هذه هي أبسط أنواع الضوابط الأمنية التي يجب تنفيذها وأبسط أنواع الثغرات الأمنية التي يمكن العثور عليها. ومع ذلك على الرغم من بساطتها من الناحية المفاهيمية إلا أن تأمين عناصر التحكم وتفكيكها بشكل عام ممل للغاية وعرضة للخطأ.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>منطق التطبيق</title><link>https://infusedev.safetag.org/ar/learning-path/4/module-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infusedev.safetag.org/ar/learning-path/4/module-5/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="حالة-استخدام">حالة استخدام&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>في أي موقع ويب تفاعلي يضع قيودًا على أنواع الإجراءات التي يمكن للمستخدمين تنفيذها، من المهم أن يفرض الموقع هذه القيود بشكل صحيح لمنع الإجراءات الضارة غير المقصودة (والمحتملة) من قبل المستخدمين الخبيثين.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="الأهداف">الأهداف&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>بعد استكمال هذا الموضوع الفرعي، يجب أن يكون الممارسون قادرين على القيام بما يلي:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>فهم مفهوم الثغرات المنطقية في التطبيقات&lt;/li>
&lt;li>تحديد وفهم الفئات الفرعية الشائعة لثغرات منطق التطبيق بما في ذلك:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>الضوابط من جانب العميل&lt;/li>
&lt;li>عدم وجود حد لمعدل/تقديم طلبات متعددة&lt;/li>
&lt;li>تضاربات التقريب&lt;/li>
&lt;li>تجاوز خطوات العملية&lt;/li>
&lt;li>تزييف الطلبات عبر المواقع&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="main-section">Main Section&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>تُعدّ ثغرات منطق التطبيق (تسمى في كثير من الأحيان ثغرات منطق الأعمال) فئة من الثغرات المجمّعة على نطاق واسع والتي تتعلق بالعمليات التي يقوم بها التطبيق نفسه على عكس ثغرات الأساسية في التقنيات التي يستخدمها التطبيق. إذا شعرت بأن هذا التعريف مربك فلست الوحيد لأن ما يشكل ثغرة في منطق الأعمال مقابل فئة أخرى هو موضع نزاع محتدم. يتمثل موقف إنفيوز (Infuse) بأن التعريف الفعلي لا يهم كثيرًا وأن السرعة أكثر أهمية من التعريفات الدقيقة ونشجعك على الحفاظ على التركيز على ثغرات نفسها وتطوير رؤية لفئات الثغرات التي تكون منطقية بالنسبة لك والحفاظ على المرونة في التصنيف عند مناقشة الثغرات مع الآخرين.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interpersonal Skills for Web Application Security</title><link>https://infusedev.safetag.org/ar/learning-path/4/module-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infusedev.safetag.org/ar/learning-path/4/module-6/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When interacting with individuals and organizations who operate web applications, self-awareness is necessary to check the nature of the digital protector relationship, provide useful and not fear-mongering advice or services. It is critical to frame your technical work within a sound risk assessment of the reality of the web application and its users.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After completing this subtopic, practitioners should be able to do the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Self reflect on the digital protector relationship with a client within web application assessment work and reporting&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Simplify and filter findings and explain them in a way which makes sense to the needs and threat models of the organization and its stakeholders&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Maintain an awareness of the limits of your own knowledge and ability&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Communicate in a non fear-mongering way about vulnerabilities and weaknesses&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Conduct a broader risk analysis of a web application based on the political, social, economic, and technical realities which surround it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="main-section">Main Section&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Your work in web application security assessment must remain contextualized within the frame of the organization which operates or hosts the application, the people who utilize it (and of their devices), the interpersonal relationships you have with these people, the nature of the web application itself, the data stored or processed on it, the legal realities which prevail over the application, and a solid risk assessment of all these elements. Let’s unpack these elements and consider a self-critique of your role as a digital protector.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>